[Opening Music Fades In]
Welcome to the Untold History of India.
Today, we revisit the spark that lit the fire of independence – the Revolt of 1857.
It was not just a mutiny. It was India’s first major struggle against British colonial rule.
The revolt began on 10th May 1857 in Meerut.
Angry Indian sepoys of the British East India Company rose up in rebellion.
The cause? Greased cartridges rumored to be laced with cow and pig fat.
Deeply offensive to both Hindu and Muslim beliefs.
But the fire was fueled by years of resentment – economic exploitation, cultural disrespect.
And racial discrimination.
From Delhi to Kanpur, Lucknow to Jhansi – brave leaders rose.
Mangal Pandey, Rani Lakshmibai, Tantia Tope, Bahadur Shah Zafar.
The British called it a “mutiny”. But for Indians, it was the First War of Independence.
Though eventually suppressed, it ignited a national consciousness.
It sowed the seeds for a freedom movement that would never die.
Let’s remember their sacrifice – and keep the flame of freedom alive.
[Outro Music Fades In]
This was Episode 1 of the Indian Independence Series.
Like, Share, and Subscribe for the next episode.